# **I PRABU**

### **Database Support Engineer**

iprabu1409@gmail.com +91 9944030828 Nagercoil,India www.linkedin.com/in/iprabu14

www.github.com/iPrabu14

# **OBJECTIVE**

To provide the company with the maximum knowledge that I have gained till now and be able to learn while working on a professional platform along with a motto of acquiring a lot of new skills that the company can nurture me with. The primary aim is to learn about the inexperienced aspects and functioning of an IT organisation.

# **EXPERIENCE**

**Database Support Engineer** 

#### **GK Microsystems**

Apr 2022 - 2024\* Nagercoil

- •I have experience working on database management and contributing to applications. My tasks involved ensuring efficient data organization, retrieval, and management.
- Reported Development using SQL queries and Crystal Reports and Business Objects.
- •Installed, configured, and maintained database server software and related products.

Junior System Administrator

#### **Perfect Systems**

Aug 2021 - Mar 2022 Nagercoil

- Configured and maintained adiverse range of systems including servers, databases, and networking equipment, utilizing technologies such as Linux, Windows Server, and VMware.
- Provided support to local end users and remote users Hardware software and ApplicationProblems.

## **INTERNSHIPS**

Hardware and Networking - Kaassiv InfoTech, Chennai.

Web App Development - Trinity Soft. Technologies, Tvm.

### **PROJECTS**

### Multilevel Histogram Specification for Image Enhancement.

Multilevel histogram specification is a technique used in image enhancement to manipulate the histogram of an image to match a specified histogram.

Histogram is a graphical representation that shows the distribution of pixel intensities values in an image. It displays the frequency of occurrence of each intensity level.

#### Memory Challenge Game.

Developed a dynamic and challenging "Memory Challenge Game" using HTML,CSS, and JavaScript. The game interface presents four distinct colors, requiring players to memorize and replicate the sequence of colors clicked in each round.

The game mechanics involve remembering and replicating the sequence accurately any deviation results in the termination of the game.

# **CERTIFIED COURSES**

Python

**GUVI Geek Networks** 

Aug 2023

The Complete Web Development Bootcamp

Udemy

Nov 2022

Foundation in Hardware and Networking

**Networkz Systems** 

Aug 2020 -Oct 2020 Nagercoil
Diploma in Advanced Network
Administration

**Networkz Systems** 

Aug 2020 -Oct 2020 Nagercoil

# **SKILL SETS**

Microsoft SQLSeverPostgreSQL

• Database Administration • Performance Tuning

•SQL Server Management Studio

•Python •MsAccess •MsExcel

Web Development

# **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor of Technology** 

Anna University 2016- 2020

Ponjesly College of

Engineering Nagercoil

**Higher Secondary Certificate** 

State Board,TN 2015–2016

Government Higher

Secondary School Kattathurai

**Secondary School Leaving Certificate** 

State Board,TN 2014-2015

**Government Higher** 

Secondary School Kattathurai